http://www.retireinvest.com.au/privacy-policy

About RI AdviceThe value of adviceFinancial advice and youComplimentary Financial Wealth CheckNewsFinancial EducationFind an adviserFAQAbout usOur TeamOur communityGet in touchAdviser Login Pay Your Invoice
Privacy StatementThe Privacy Policy contains information about:the circumstances in which we or one of our related entities may collect personal information (including health and other sensitive information) from other sources (including from a third party);how to access personal information and seek correction of personal information; andhow you can raise concerns that we or one of our related entities has breached the Privacy Act or an applicable code and how we or our related entity will deal with those matters.At RI Advice Group we are committed to ensuring the confidentiality and security of your personal information (including health and other sensitive information). We are bound by the Privacy Act and the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs).How we use your informationRI Advice Group collects your personal information (including health and other sensitive information) in order for one of its authorised representatives (that is, your adviser and/or the practice where he/she works) to provide you with financial products and services. In order to undertake the management and administration of products and services, it may be necessary for us to disclose your personal information (including health and other sensitive information) to certain third parties.We and your adviser will collect and use information about you during the course of your relationship with each of us.It is important that the information we hold about you is up to date. You must let your adviser know when information you have provided has changed.Collection, use and disclosure of informationWe may use and disclose your personal information (including health and other sensitive information) for the following purposes:to assist in providing you with products and services;to consider your request for a product or service;to enable RI Advice Group or another member of the IOOF Group to provide you with a product or service that was recommended to you by your adviser;to tell you about other products or services that may be of interest to you;to assist in arrangements with other organisations (for example product issuers or alliance partners) in relation to the promotion or provision of a product or service;to manage the relationship between you and your adviser and any accounts or policies which you hold, and perform other administrative and operational tasks (including but not limited to risk management, systems development and testing, credit scoring, staff training and market, customer satisfaction, investment research and to undertake analytics activities);to consider any concerns or complaints you raise against RI Advice Group and/or your adviser and to manage any legal action involving RI Advice Group;to identify, prevent or investigate any fraud, unlawful activity or misconduct (or suspected fraud, unlawful activity or misconduct);to identify you or establish your tax status under any Australian or foreign legislation, regulation or treaty or pursuant to an agreement with any tax authority; oras required by relevant laws, regulations, codes of practice and external payment systems.We may disclose your personal information (including health and other sensitive information) to another licensee in order to enable you to continue to receive financial products and services in the following circumstances:where your adviser dies or their arrangements with us terminate;where our authorised representative becomes an authorised representative of another licensee; orwhere our authorised representative sells all or part of its business to another licensee.Absence of relevant informationIf you do not provide some or all of the information requested, RI Advice Group may be unable to provide you with products or services.Information required by lawWe may be required by relevant laws to collect certain information from you. Details of laws that require us to collect information about individuals (personal information) and why these laws require us to collect personal information are contained in the Privacy Policy which can be found at ioof.com.au/privacy.Providing your information to othersWe may provide your personal information (including health and other sensitive information) to:an authorised representative of ours (including your adviser) for the purposes outlined in this document;IOOF and any related entity of IOOF which may use the information to carry out IOOF's functions and activities; organisations, including those in an alliance with RI Advice Group or IOOF, to distribute, manage and administer our products and services, carry out business functions and undertake analytics activities;any agent, contractor or service provider of RI Advice Group or its authorised representative, engaged to carry out or assist with its functions and activities (for example, office support or paraplanning services, IT support providers and mailing houses);an organisation that assists RI Advice Group to identify, prevent or investigate fraud, unlawful activity or misconduct;regulatory bodies, government agencies, law enforcement bodies and courts;other parties RI Advice Group is authorised or required by law or court/tribunal order to disclose information to;any person who introduces you to RI Advice Group;your referee(s);your employer;your partner or spouse where they have sought advice jointly with you; oryour authorised agents; your executor, administrator or trustee in bankruptcy; your legal representative; your attorney; or anyone else acting for you.Where your adviser discloses your personal information to recipients which are (1) located outside Australia and/or (2) either not established in or do not carry on business in Australia, he/she will inform you of those countries in the Adviser Profile of our FSG.Marketing and PrivacyWe and other members of the IOOF Group may use your personal information to send you information about our financial products and services from time to time.We and IOOF may also disclose your personal information to our related companies or organisations in an arrangement or alliance with us and/or IOOF to share information for marketing purposes. This is to enable them or IOOF to tell you about a product or service offered by them or a third party with whom they have an arrangement.If you do not want us or IOOF to use and disclose your information as set out above, phone Customer Services on 1800 738 473 to withdraw your consent.Privacy PolicyThe Privacy Policy is available at ioof.com.au/privacy and contains information about:the circumstances in which we or one of our related entities may collect personal information (including health and other sensitive information) from other sources (including from a third party);how to access personal information and seek correction of personal information; andhow you can raise concerns that we or one of our related entities has breached the Privacy Act or an applicable code and how we or our related entity will deal with those matters.Personal information you provide about someone elseIf you give us personal information (including health and other sensitive information) about someone else, please show them a copy of this notice and direct them to the Privacy Policy available at ioof.com.au/privacy so that they may understand the manner in which their personal information (including health and other sensitive information) may be used or disclosed in connection with your dealings with us.
